<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Spill The Tea]]></title><description><![CDATA[Spill The Tea]]></description><link>https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 17:47:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[How do you make a rented apartment feel like a home?]]></title><description><![CDATA[My husband and I have been renting apartments for quite some time. Moving from Texas to North Carolina and now finally to Massachusetts,...]]></description><link>https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/post/how-do-you-make-a-rented-apartment-feel-like-a-home</link><guid isPermaLink="false">65178f891a413df203617194</guid><category><![CDATA[Decor and Styling]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 14:32:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_df35177da1204503b8fac9825985f8e5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My husband and I have been renting apartments for quite some time. Moving from Texas to North Carolina and now finally to Massachusetts, it’s been a real ride. I said finally because Mass feels like home. So naturally we’ve been apartment hopping for a while now. A couple of things that may cross one’s mind in this constant state of change is, do I even buy new furniture? What’s the point of decorating? I’ve always tried to make our place(s) feel like home but the constant move kinda limited me from doing much when it came to home decor. I did my best to make the apartment feel like home with some mismatched preloved pieces. But now that we’ve finalized our destination, I feel like I can finally let my creative side pop!


I am a patron of arts so if I were to make this new apartment feel like my place, there would be lots of artsy things! My husband is easy-going and he usually likes what I like so we rarely have creative differences. He is big on privacy so if my art is going to interfere with his privacy, that’s just not going to work out. Otherwise, we are good.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_df35177da1204503b8fac9825985f8e5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
My style is a mix of European and bohemian. I like vibrant colors that pop and also a basic classic beige-white-brown combo. Although just an amateur, art is my expression. Living away from home is difficult so I always keep a family album for my comfort.</p>

<p>And of course, our home cannot feel like a home without some house plants. I’m usually not good at keepin’ the plants alive..don’t come at me now, I try my best. I water them, and let them have enough sunlight for photosynthesis. But something always goes wrong. I don’t think I understand the science of nurturing plants. But this time, I met with a family friend, you can call him the plant doctor. He was kind enough to give me tips on providing a healthy environment. Hesitantly and of course, with the support of my lovely husband, we bought 2 plants. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_667a3ab52c2f4e8ba5267fcb99ebcf78~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>And not just any plants, bonsais! I love bonsai. I always have. And I swear to God I saw bonsais at Costco this one time. I like Costco, they sell quality goods for a good price. It’s always a win. Well, you do end up spending more somehow..has anyone else experienced this? No? Just me I guess. So anyhoo, the bonsais are doing great. I’m a bit skeptical since the winter is coming, but we shall see. Fingers crossed!


How do you make the place feel like home? What’s your style?</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vatan]]></title><description><![CDATA[One thing you should know about me is that I’m a sucker for Indian food. I can eat roti, sabzi, dal and rice every single day. I’m pretty...]]></description><link>https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/post/vatan</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6517913f754a73455d488746</guid><category><![CDATA[Food]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 04:00:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_389f4ede29f0469ba509dfdd27adb3b4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One thing you should know about me is that I’m a sucker for Indian food. I can eat roti, sabzi, dal and rice every single day. I’m pretty basic that way. I’m a Marathi girl married to a Gujarati guy. So although my husband and I are both from India, we come from different cultures. Different cultures, different languages, different styles of cooking. But we make it work. Mostly because we speak the same language- the language of love. Just kidding, it's Hindi and English. So vatan. What’s vatan you may ask. Vatan is magic. Vatan is everything you’ll need to cook a delicious meal. Vatan will save you time. Vatan will give you delight. Okay, okay let’s not overdo it.


In all seriousness though, vatan is simply a kind of pesto. You toss some roughly chopped onions, some garlic cloves or an entire bulb, and desiccated coconut in oil and sauté until fragrant. Once done, allow the mixture to cool down before putting it in the blender. The shelf life is a couple of months if you freeze it.

</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_389f4ede29f0469ba509dfdd27adb3b4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
I put vatan in every dish I make. I’ve put it in sabzi, chicken, seafood, and once in a very specific rice cuisine. Just add a tablespoon or two of vatan after sautéing onions and before adding any condiments and it will enhance the flavor of your dish- I promise. This is a family recipe. I learned it from my mother.


Do you use vatan while cooking? What are some tips and tricks you’ve learned from your family?</p>


<p>
</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mixing art with science-Interview with a PhD candidate]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hi, my name is Ea, and I am a first year PhD candidate studying Applied Biological Chemistry at Tokyo University of Agriculture and...]]></description><link>https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/post/abc-interview-with-a-phd-candidate</link><guid isPermaLink="false">65174fcfce820cf8dea34df8</guid><category><![CDATA[STEM Up: Women In STEM]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 22:46:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_0eb822936cf14721a6c517803cca0406~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_724,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, my name is Ea, and I am a first year PhD candidate studying Applied Biological Chemistry at Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology (TUAT). I did undergrad in Chemistry from Visayas State University in Leyte, Philippines and Master’s degree in Agriculture from TUAT. As a PhD candidate I am working on glycoproteins found in central nervous system. Funny story, as I take hundreds of photos of the brain, I was inspired to convert these pictures into art as a project called Experiments in Art (EA). With this I hope to start a trend where artists use science as inspiration and scientists can look at their work in a different way.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_0eb822936cf14721a6c517803cca0406~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_724,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><em>1. How would you describe your role?</em></p>
<p>I study glycans (polysaccharides), specifically those that bonds to glycoproteins. With the help of different chemical tools that we have developed in the lab, we study how these glycoproteins change in the brain especially in the node of Ranvier, which are unmyelinated regions in the axon that are important for fast conduction of nerve impulses.</p>

<p><em>2. What are some challenges you have faced in this research?</em></p>
<p>I grew up in Leyte, Philippines so as much as the environment was nurturing for my growth as a student there weren’t enough opportunities like exposure to other  scientists or science programs as there are in Manila or some place else. The research opportunities were limited as the labs were not fully advanced, and for students in the province it is a big hindering factor that majority of the programs supported on media and private companies are only in Manila. And now that I'm in Japan working on my PhD, language barrier is proving to be a challenge since I spend a lot of time in Japanese laboratory. However, my lab mates and professor are very supportive, so this helps me cope with this challenge.</p>

<p><em>3. What made you choose this STEM discipline? Were you inspired by someone?</em></p>
<p>Funny you should ask, because both my parents are scientists. My dad is a Biochemist and my mom is a Soil Scientist. Growing up I was always exposed to science and my first experiment was making antibacterial soap with my dad using flowers near my school for an elementary science fair. We won first place. Personally, I think it was definitely a way for me and my dad to bond, and my mom was also very supportive so it wasn’t hard to fall in love with the field.</p>
<p>I would say the biggest influence were definitely be my parents, followed by my high school and elementary science teachers. First time I heard “molecular biology” was freshmen year in high school and I just remember being so amazed with that word. I didn’t pursue the major during college but now with my work as a biological chemistry PhD candidate, I’m using molecular biology techniques.</p>
<p>To sum this up, I love working in the lab, and I also loved researching as a kid..so this and support from my folks and university proved to be very influential for me in choosing this very STEM discipline.</p>

<p><em>4. What’s the best way to enter your field? What kind of experience or skills should one possess to build a successful career in the same?</em></p>
<p>There are multiple ways of entering this field so I am not quite sure which one's the best. I was fortunate enough to grow up in a family that is in academia. Both my parents are professors and my dad is in the same field as me. For grade school, I did experiments on antibacterial soap using flowers near my school, in high school I studied about proteolytic properties of local plant species and how it can be related to Alzheimer's disease, in undergrad I was a Chemistry major and my thesis was on the alpha-glucosidase inhibitory activity of indigenous plant species in the Philippines and how it can be related to Diabetes. So I guess what I am trying to say here is that I was exposed to lab environment at a very young age and my parents supported me in every step which I think played a big role and that encouraged me to work hard and aim for higher education. Since I am still very new in my career I am not yet fit to say what it takes to be successful but based on what I've learned so far, grit and perseverance paired with curiosity and creativity goes a long way. One might face failures and frustrating moments on a regular basis but the best thing to do is to just scratch that mistake and go back to the drawing board. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_0a86746e27bb4892b182deae60fdb6a9~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_724,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><em>5. What are some cool things that people in your profession work on?</em></p>
<p>We work on cell biology, elucidating protein crystal structure using X-ray crystallography (super cool technique that allows us to see the 3D structure of a protein and how it interacts with different molecules), brain research, genome editing, modifying proteins so they are expressed more which is important in medicine, food, and fuel industries.</p>

<p><em>6. What keeps you going in your research? What’s next for your career?</em></p>
<p>There are a lot of things that helps me to keep going in my research but to name a few, a supportive lab group, interesting research topic, and of course full scholarship definitely plays a big role.</p>
<p>After my PhD, I am eyeing on going back to Philippines to help develop STEM fields in the country and to strengthen the collaboration between Filipino and Japanese universities.</p>

<p><em>7. What do you think can help get girls into STEM?</em></p>
<p>Grit, willingness to learn, hard work, confidence and relationships that we build with people can help us move forward in STEM. There may be less women in STEM right now but that should not discourage us from being in the field. The advantage of being less in number is that it means there are still many spaces to fill, and as a woman in STEM, I encourage you girls to fill that space! Collaboration is key, for men and women alike. As long as we keep this in mind, we can build a symbiotic relationship with men and I hope this encourages us girls to share our ideas knowing that our thoughts as women are very much needed. A raise of the hand in a conference, an e-mail to a professor stating your intention to work in lab, writing that application letter, googling "scholarships for developing countries", picking one that is applicable to you, asking your colleagues to help you apply for grad school. Sometimes the guts to initiate is all it takes to get into STEM. </p>

<p><em>8. What message would you like to give to our young readers?</em></p>
<p>Past generations have worked hard to provide women a platform to be visible and heard in STEM and related fields. There is no need to be intimidated anymore. If you feel like STEM is something you want to pursue, go for it! Find a role model or be your own. The perspective of a woman is important in STEM not only for representation but because our brains can offer insights that will compliment that of men, and this is important for the progression of knowledge and learning.</p>


<p>Hope you enjoyed Ea's interview.  To know more about what Ea is up to, check out her journey at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/eakriistine/" target="_blank" >@eakriistine</a></p>
<p>Follow us for more inspiring STEM interviews.</p>
<p>Want to make a difference with your STEM story? Email us at <a href="mailto:codejammies@gmail.com" target="_blank" >codejammies@gmail.com</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 Interesting Finds On Etsy]]></title><description><![CDATA[My then-boyfriend, now-husband and I have been together for 4 years so needless to say, we have spoiled each other with countless gifts....]]></description><link>https://codejammies.wixsite.com/spillthetea/post/8-interesting-finds-on-etsy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">651705d8cb09432cd1a08d31</guid><category><![CDATA[Gifts]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 17:25:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_d35fe70f6ef34ddd98dfb5ca646ab834~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_529,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Sally</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My then-boyfriend, now-husband and I have been together for 4 years so needless to say, we have spoiled each other with countless gifts. From simple handmade and/or expensive store-bought gifts to couple's spa sessions we have done everything! So lately it's been a real challenge finding something interesting and I am sure we are not alone. Just a couple months back we celebrated our first wedding anniversary and like a good wife I spent hours on the internet looking for a perfect present. I kept looking and looking, hopping from one site to another with no luck. But just when I was about to give up and settle for a common store-bought gift, an ad popped up on my Instagram feed and swept me off my feet. There it was Etsy, saving me yet another time. Honestly, I have been a big fan of Etsy for quite some time because it never disappoints if you are into uncommon finds. So without wasting more time, let's dig right in!</p>
<hr><h2><strong>Wooden Street Cutouts from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/1Man1Garage?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=256146118#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>1Man1Garage</strong></a></h2><p>Of course I am going to start with the present I gave my husband on our anniversary! These guys literally saved me during my desperate times- I was frustrated and running short on time but they were kind enough to squeeze me in and got my personalized order ready in just 2 days! Their wooden street cutouts and city maps are to die for and also come in different sizes. How cool is that?</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_d35fe70f6ef34ddd98dfb5ca646ab834~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_529,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>HD Wood Portrait Pallet from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/Rawkrft?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=725338071" target="_blank" ><strong>Rawkrft</strong></a></h2><p>This one is my personal favorite. Funny story- I was a bit skeptical when I ordered this for the first time but when it arrived...hallelujah! It turned out SO good. Rich look and great picture quality. I liked it so much that I gifted this to 3 of my friends and they absolutely loved it.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_fd2969a1c8fa40e687eca56fe9f2ae6d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_794,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Friends Apartment Door Portrait Frame from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/PbarkerStudio?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=779872020#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>PbarkerStudio</strong></a></h2><p>Hold on..did someone say F.R.I.E.N.D.S? and then an actual miniature of Monica's apartment door which also is a legit photo frame?! OHH-MYYY-GODDDD!! Could I be more excited?</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_41b49b00a77e4354abac1712ff80112f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_923,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Friends Yellow Door Frame from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/TucsonDream?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=589193530#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>TucsonDream</strong></a></h2><p>Yet another great F.R.I.E.N.D.S fanatic find on Etsy. The iconic yellow frame on Monica Geller's apartment door at a very affordable price!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_0244617a35a340cd8a844a52d5224b56~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_778,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Handmade</strong> <strong>Animal Slippers from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/DarkaYarka?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=641867229#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>DarkaYarka</strong></a></h2><p>Now hang on I know what you are thinking, animal slippers are neither new nor uncommon but before questioning my find, you got to check these babies out! These are not any regular supermarket animal/poop slippers, these are premium custom-made handmade woollen slippers which actually look pretty convincing. Well done DarkaYarka. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_5b82ba0c09254383aa4661a8999d5e89~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_556,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Pressed Flower Jewelry from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/MARIAELA?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=754915644#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>MARIAELA</strong></a></h2><p>I discovered this store sometime in January of this year and have been a fan ever since. She makes the most beautiful handmade jewelry and not just with pressed flowers but also sand, glass, stones and yes of course metal. I bought a beautiful set of wolf earrings (big GOT fan) and an electroformed mother of pearl moon statement ring and I am absolutely happy with my purchase.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_28e060b1862040b3aab9467285852235~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_690,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>Actual Kids Drawing Necklace from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/CaitlynMinimalist?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=210793283#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>CaitlynMinimalist</strong></a></h2><p>These guys will transform your kid's art into necklaces! But of course doodles not limited to just kids, you can also print one of your drawings or doodles and flaunt it around your neck. Freeze your special doodles for-eva.❤️</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_50e9dbe1ec1b4345906ae91a7cbb5c04~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_794,h_794,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2><strong>The Office Illustration Magnet from </strong><a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/thefoundretail?ref=simple-shop-header-name&#38;listing_id=692511241#shop-info-banner" target="_blank" ><strong>thefoundretail</strong></a></h2><p>Again one of the many things I ordered from Etsy. You can find some really awesome pins, magnets, stickers and tags here at a very affordable price! P.S. this store is in my favorites. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/02b093_c4c4a44590884056b07329e5117ab051~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_768,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Came across more uncommon finds? Comment below and let me know!</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this read. Until next time!</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>